

#### SYSTEM SECURITY ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE RESEARCHER · SOFTWARE REPOSITORY MINER

731 Lexington, New York City, NY 10022, U.S.

□ (+1) 213-884-8846 | ■ ducmle@usc.edu | ★ lemduc.io | □ lemduc | □ lemduc | ⑤ lemduc

## **Summary**\_

Blends research experience in Software Engineering, Data Mining and System Security with diverse and practical trainings in the software industries of Vietnam, S.Korea and U.S. to offer solid skills in software design and development. Experiences include (1) mining software repositories/big data, (2) system security, (3) architecture design, recovery, and analysis, (4) software product line engineering.

## **Education**

#### **University of Southern California (USC)**

Los Angeles, U.S.

 ${\sf PhD} \ {\sf in} \ {\sf Computer} \ {\sf Science}, \\ {\sf Software} \ {\sf Architecture} \ {\sf Research} \ {\sf Group} \ ({\sf SoftArch})$ 

Aug. 2013 - July. 2018

• Advisor: Prof. Nenad Medvidović

GPA: 3.87/4.00

### Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MSc in Information Technology Convergence Engineering, Software Engineering Lab (SELab)

Aug. 2010 - May. 2012

Advisor: Prof. Kyo Chul Kang

4ug. 2010 - May. 2012

## Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

Hanoi, Vietnam

BSc in Information Technology (Magna Cum Laude)

Aug. 2005 - May. 2010

Advisors: Assoc. Prof. Huynh Quyet Thang (HUST), Dr. Martin Nordio (ETH Zurich)

GPA: 8.07/10.00

GPA: 95.9/100.0

# **Work Experience**

Bloomberg L.P. New York, New York, U.S.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July. 2018 - PRESENT

- · A member of the System Security team at Bloomberg
- Maintain and extend Bloomberg Single Sign On system.
- Manage the access control of Bloomberg's computer system

#### **NEC Laboratories America, Inc.**

Princeton, New Jersey, U.S.

RESEARCH INTERN - COMPUTER SECURITY GROUP

May. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- · Analyzed activity logs of PCs in the company's internal networks and extract patterns of safe activities.
- Built different prediction models for those patterns.
- Implemented the approach and integrated into Automated Security Intelligence (ASI) system of NEC.

#### **Veritas Technologies LLC**

Culver, California, U.S.

 ${\tt Software\ Engineering\ Intern\ -EV.Cloud\ Project,\ Platform\ Team}$ 

May. 2016 - Aug. 2016

- · Applied topic modeling and machine learning techniques to intelligently suggest retention policies for customers' emails.
- Implemented and verified the proposed approach on Enron dataset using Spark, Hadoop, Cassandra, and Spring Framework.
- Was selected to present at VERITAS Cutting Edge 2016.

## **Samsung Research America**

Irvine, California, U.S.

RESEARCH INTERN - ADVANCED PRINTING SOFTWARE LAB

Jun. 2015 - Sep. 2015

- Completed the end-to-end scenario of extracting UP (Unified Interfaces of Samsung Printers) variability information from an actual MFP (Multi-Functions Printers), representing this in a UP variability model, editing this information, and using it to configure a running simulator instance.
- · This involved design and implementation using different technologies: OSGi, EMF, Eclipse plug-ins, REST-ful webservices, UI development.

Dasan Handysoft

Seoul, S.Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

**HDC Media Vietnam** 

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

- Designed the server architecture of HandyUC 5.0, a platform providing various types of communication to enterprises, including email, instant messaging, and video conferencing.
- Implemented communication protocols of HandyUC, including XMPP protocol, Handysoft's legacy protocol, and a Http-based protocol.

PHP DEVELOPER & ASTERISK PBX ADMINISTRATOR

Hanoi, Vietnam Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2010

- Developed a movie website based on Joomla platform to provide video contents to customers.
- Maintained and adapted Asterisk PBX system of the company to meet the company's requirements.

SEPTEMBER 15, 2019 DUC M. LE · CURRICULUM VITAE



**Programming** Java (Proficient), Python, Linux Shell, PHP, JavaScript, C/C++

Frameworks SAML, OAuth2, Open ID, Spark, Spring, OSGi, EMF, GWT, Joomla, Liferay, Microsoft Azure

Databases MySQL, MongoDB

Others Agile Development, CI/CD, LTEX, SVN, Git, Asterisk PBX

## Research Experience

#### **Architectural Change and Decay in Open-source Software Systems**

Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURAL RESEARCH GROUP, USC

Feb. 2014 - July. 2018

- Reversed architectures of over 800 versions of 23 open-source systems, totaling over 120 MLOCs.
- Found evolution trends related to architectural changes in software systems, rate of architectural decay occurrences, correlations among implementation decisions and architectural changes.
- Use implicit problems, e.g., architectural- and code-smells, in combination with explicit problems, e.g. reported issues and bugs, to provide an accurate, systematic and in depth approach to predict potential system problems, particularly bugs.
- · Cooperated with Huawei USA in a study of how to adapt the company's codebase to architectural changes in new Android versions.

#### **Privacy Preserving in Distributed Computation**

Los Angeles, CA, U.S. May. 2014 - Aug. 2014

Software Architectural Research Group, USC

- Studied sTile, a tile-based architecture, which tackles the problem of distributing computation onto cloud, while providing probabilistic guarantees that agents compromising parts of the cloud wouldn't be able to learn the private data and the nature of the computation.
- Deployed and evaluated a prototype of sTile on several main cloud services (Azure, EC2, Google Cloud).

#### Impact Analysis of Software Requirement Change based on Feature Relationships

Pohang, S.Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING LAB, POSTECH

Sep. 2012 - Feb. 2013

- Reversed feature models based on variation points and variants embedded by C preprocessor.
- · Verified consistency between designed models and reversed models and provided refactoring advice.
- Integrated into VULCAL Workbench, a CASE tool that supports software product line engineering.

### CloudStudio - Enabling distributed projects to produce software "on the cloud"

Hanoi, Vietnam

**ETH ZURICH & HUST**Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2010

- Created the initial version of CloudStudio, an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) enabling globally distributed software projects and producing software "on the cloud".
- Developed the following features: project management, code editor, project compilation, group communication.

## **Select Publications**

#### An Empirical Study of Architectural Decay in Open-Source Software Systems

Seattle, U.S.

Duc M. LE, Daniel Link, Arman Shahbazian, Nenad Medvidovic

• Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Software Architecture (ICSA 2018)

May. 2018

#### **Recovering architectural design decisions**

ARMAN SHAHBAZIAN, YOUN KYU LEE, **DUC M. LE**, YURI BRUN, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

Seattle, U.S. May. 2018

Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Software Architecture (ICSA 2018)

## A Large-Scale Study of Architectural Evolution in Open-Source Software Systems

POOYAN BEHNAMGHADER\*, DUC M. LE\*, JOSHUA GARCIA, DANIEL LINK, ARMAN SHAHBAZIAN, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

Jun. 2017

115

• Empirical Software Engineering (EMSE) Journal

## Toward a Classification Framework for Software Architectural Smells

Feb. 2017

Duc M. Le, Daniel Link, Yixue Zhao, Arman Shahbazian, Chris Mattmann, Nenad Medvidovic

reb. 2017

US

Technical Report at USC Center for Systems and Software Engineering

### Architectural-Based Speculative Analysis to Predict Bugs in a Software System

Austin, U.S.

**DUC M. LE**, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

May. 2016

 $\bullet \ \ \mathsf{Proceeding} \ \mathsf{of} \ \mathsf{the} \ \mathsf{38th} \ \mathsf{International} \ \mathsf{Conference} \ \mathsf{on} \ \mathsf{Software} \ \mathsf{Engineering} \ (\mathsf{ICSE}), \mathsf{Doctoral} \ \mathsf{Symposium} \ \mathsf{track}$ 

#### **Relating Architectural Decay and Sustainability of Software Systems**

Venice, Italy

DUC M. LE, CARLOS CARRILLO, RAFAEL CAPILLA, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

Apr. 2016

Proceeding of the 13th Working IEEE/IFIP Conference on Software Architecture (WICSA)

#### An Empirical Study of Architectural Change in Open-Source Software Systems

Florence, Italy

Duc M. Le, Pooyan Behnamghader, Joshua Garcia, Daniel Link, Arman Shahbazian, Nenad Medvidovic

• Proceeding of the 12th Working Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR)

May. 2015

### Validating consistency between feature model and its implementation

DUC M. LE, LEE HYESUN, KYO C. KANG, KEUN LEE

• Proceeding of the 13th International Conference on Software Reuse (ICSR)

Pisa, Italy Jun. 2013

## **Rel**evant Coursework

Software Engineering Software Architecture Software Testing

Advanced Algorithms Artificial Intelligence Decision Support Systems Machine Learning Natural Language Processing Advanced Operating Systems

Database Systems Information and Data Modeling Information Security

## **Honors & Awards**.

| 2018 | Best Paper Award, ICSA 2018  | Seattle, WA, USA      |
|------|--|-----------------------|
| 2016 | 'Thesis in Three' - Best Presentation Award, Doctoral Symposium, ICSE 2016   | Austin, TX, USA       |
| 2015 | Awardee, ACM SigSoft CAPS Travel Support for attending ICSE 2015             | Florence, Italy       |
| 2014 | Awardee, USC Doctoral Student Summer Institute Award                         | Los Angeles, CA, U.S. |
| 2013 | Awardee, Vietnam Education Foundation Fellowship                             | U.S.                  |
| 2011 | Best Poster Prize, 3rd International Symposium on IT Convergence Engineering | Pohang, S.Korea       |
| 2010 | Awardee, Certificate of Merit for Excellent Graduation Achievement           | Hanoi, Vietnam        |